Xiaoning,
小涂
there's a document.
有一个文件
Take a good look at it.
好好看一下
Okay.
好
Xiaoning,
小涂
such a serious expression.
这么郑重其事的表情
Land a big client?
挖到大客户了
No,
没有
I'm signing up for
转正考试
the permanent employee exam.
我正报名
Pass the written test,
考过了笔试
you're closer to getting permanent contract.
离转正又近了一步
Keep it up.
加油
Thanks, Fanggang.
谢谢小赵哥
Everyone,
各位
I just came back from HR.
我刚从人事部回来啊
Today is Mr. Ji's
今天呢是纪总
first birthday
到咱们部门的
in our department,
第一个生日
so HR
按照惯例呢
is preparing
人事部会给他
a birthday cake for him.
准备一个生日蛋糕
Who's going to pick it up?
待会儿谁过去取一趟
I'll go.
我去吧
All right,
行
you go later then.
那待会儿你去啊
Okay.
好
Today is his birthday.
今天是他的生日
Ouch!
好烫
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
I heard you landed
听说你又拉了个
another big client.
大客户啊
Come on, it's the end of the year.
到了年底还不放松放松
You're rat-racing us.
真是卷死我们啊
Xiaoning,
小涂
come to my office.
来我办公室一趟
I need you to check some receipts.
有几张票据需要对一下
Okay.
好
Mr. Ji,
纪总
here's what you asked for.
你要的东西
Is it your birthday today?
你今天过生日啊
Sit down.
坐
What are you doing?
干吗
We're in your office.
办公室呢
What if someone sees us?
万一被人看见了呢
Don't move.
别乱动
Just act natural. They can't see.
自然一点他们看不到
You're so careless.
怎么这么不小心啊
Does it hurt?
疼不疼啊
No.
不疼
But if someone sees us,
这要是被人看见了
it wouldn't be good.
不大好吧
All done.
好了
Why didn't you
你过生日
tell me it's your birthday?
为什么不跟我说一声啊
As your future wife,
我作为你的准老婆
I didn't even know.
都不知道你过生日
Am I too negligent?
我是不是太不称职了
Actually, I've always wanted
其实我一直都挺想
to make a cake
在过生日这天
with someone on my birthday.
有人陪我一起做个蛋糕
But
但是
the company
公司好像
is already preparing a cake for you.
给你准备蛋糕了
But I don't like cream.
但是我不太喜欢奶油
I prefer the cake base.
我喜欢蛋糕坯
Cake base with coffee.
蛋糕坯配咖啡
Sure,
好
got it.
我知道了
So, it's settled then.
那这么说定了
Xu Li,
许力
Li Xiang,
李想
today's
今儿啊
our boss's
是领导
first birthday
来咱们拓展一部
with section one.
第一个生日
He doesn't seem
看他这个样子
to have many friends.
应该没什么朋友
Let's celebrate
咱们下班以后
his birthday after work.
去给他过生日吧
It's sad
他一个人过生日
for him
孤零零的
to be alone.
怪可怜的
What kind of
那面粉
flour should we buy?
应该买什么样的呀
Let's use this
咱们还是用这种
low-gluten one.
低筋的吧
We also need some cornstarch
还需要一些玉米淀粉
for better texture.
口感会更好
Cornstarch...
玉米淀粉
Over there.
在那边
I'll get it.
那我自己去拿
Hello?
喂
Boss,
领导
I see you're not working late today.
我看你今儿没加班
Are you out
不会是
celebrating your birthday?
出去过生日了吧
Any plans?
有安排
No way.
怎么可能有安排
I'm at home.
我在家呢
We're all at the supermarket
大家伙都已经
near your place now.
在你家附近的超市了
We're...
我们现在
Isn't that Mr. Ji?
那不是纪总吗
-Boss. -Boss.
领导 领导
If we hadn't come,
大家伙要是不来
you'd have bought your stuff
你买完东西
and gone home alone
一个人孤零零地回家
to celebrate your birthday.
自己过生日了
How about hot pot tonight?
那今晚吃火锅呗
Sounds good.
火锅好
There's a new
正好这附近
hot pot place nearby.
新开了一家火锅店
It's good.
我也知道
Let's go,
走
I'll take you there.
我带你们去
Boss,
领导
we should
咱该节约的时候
be economical.
还是得节约
I think it's more cozy
而且我觉得啊
to eat at home.
在家里面吃氛围更好
Everyone can
大家伙
chat more comfortably.
还能聊得更畅快
Exactly.
就是
That hot pot place
那家火锅店味道
is quite good.
确实还不错
We can try it.
咱们可以试试
Don't worry,
你放心
we won't take up too much of your time.
不会耽误你太多时间的
Listen,
咱啊
let's celebrate
不出去吃
at your place.
就去你家里给你庆生
Look,
你看
we already bought the ingredients.
食材都已经买好了
Everyone can get to
大家伙也借机
know you better
跟你走进走进关系
and promote team harmony.
促进团队和谐吗
Are you worried
你该不是
your place is too messy?
怕家里面太乱了
Come on,
那你说说
which guy's place
大老爷们家里
isn't a bit messy?
有几个不乱的
Don't want us to come?
不想让我们去啊
Of course not.
当然不是
This one...
这个
I think I heard
我怎么好像听到
Xiaoning's voice?
小涂的声音了
Xiaoning?
小涂 小涂
What Xiaoning?
哪有什么小涂
Xiaoning!
小 小涂
I forgot about her.
我把小涂给忘了
She left early today.
她今天下班走得早
Did anyone tell her
你们有跟她说
about tonight's plans?
今天安排吗
No.
没有啊
Almost forgot.
忘了
I'll call her.
我给她打电话
Hurry up.
你赶紧打吧
She hung up on me!
她怎么给我挂了
I remember
我记得白天
Ms. Rao said something about
饶经理说什么
hosting a state-owned enterprise client.
要接待国企客户
State-owned enterprise client?
国企客户
When did that happen?
什么时候的事啊
I overheard it in the break room.
茶水间不经意听到的
Maybe I heard wrong.
可能听错了
No,
不对呀
she told me before leaving
下班前她还跟我说
that if it's confirmed
要是你今天过生日
today is your birthday,
确定下来了
to let her know.
就通知她
I'll call her.
我给她打个电话
We'll have hot pot
那咱们就去家里
at home.
吃火锅吧
Let's buy a few more things.
去那边再买点东西
Sure.
得嘞
Looks like there's no stopping them.
看样子是拦不住了
I'll go home and prepare.
我先回家处理现场
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
we're all here to celebrate
我们都来给领导
the boss's birthday.
过生日了
I heard
听说
you secretly met with a client.
你偷着见客户去了
That's not cool.
太不地道了吧
I told you to wait for my message.
我不是让你等我消息吗
Why are you acting up?
你抽什么风啊
She didn't go.
她没去
Okay,
好
I'll stall them.
我拖住他们
Try to buy some time.
尽量给你争取时间
Unlocked.
已开锁
Locked.
已关锁
Well,
对
let's get another one of those
这芝士嫩鸡看看
cheesy tender chickens.
还有没有再来一个
More?
还要 纪总
That's enough.
差不多了
I'm hungry.
饿了
That should be enough.
差不多了吧
Right.
是
That's enough.
差不多了
I remember
我记得那谁
someone likes something
好像挺喜欢吃那什么的
over there.
在那边
I'll go find it.
我去找找
Wait,
不是
who likes what?
哪谁喜欢吃哪什么
The birthday boy can eat
寿星说想吃什么
whatever he wants.
就吃什么吧
By the way,
那个
did you
你跟
get in touch with Xiaoning?
小涂联系到了吗
Right, right,
对 对 对
my bad.
我这脑子
I'll call her now.
打电话
So much food.
这么多
Hello, Li Xiang?
喂 李想哥
Where are you?
你现在在哪儿啊
Listen,
这样啊
we're about to go to
我们现在马上去
Mr. Ji's place for his birthday.
纪总家里给他过生日
It's a great chance
我跟你说啊
to get to know
这可是接触领导的
our boss.
大好时机啊
Share your location
等我到了
when I arrive.
咱们共享位置
Just send
那个
me the location,
你发位置给我就行
I can find it.
我能找到
Are you already there?
你们现在已经到了呀
Not yet.
还没呢
We'll be there
估计
in about ten minutes.
大概十分钟吧
Okay,
好
see you soon.
一会儿见
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
you're late.
姗姗来迟啊
Here,
来
help me with this.
拿一下
Wait,
不是 不是
Yes.
好
just hold it for a moment.
你还是稍微拿一下呗
Even if you're on the phone,
你打电话归打电话
you can still
你总不至于
help me carry things.
什么都不拿吧
And
还有啊
those in front...
前面那些
I'm telling you all.
我跟你们说
Let's hurry up.
咱们快点吧
Why are you
我说你这个人
in such a rush?
这么着急干什么
Tired, everyone?
走累了吧各位
Not too bad.
还行 还行
Good news,
跟你说个好消息
we're almost there.
就是上面
But seeing you all so tired,
不过看你这么累
let's rest a bit.
咱先歇会吧
Let me tell you
给你们介绍介绍
about this wall.
这墙壁
In my neighborhood,
我这小区里住了很多
many retirees live here.
退休的大爷大妈
Look at this wall,
咱就看这墙壁啊
they built it themselves.
都是他们亲手砌的
Every brick is eco-friendly,
每一块都是环保砖
insulated, and heat-resistant.
保温还能隔热
-And... -Boss,
而且 领导
let's talk about it later.
回头再介绍吧
What do you mean later?
什么回头介绍
I was just explaining these bricks.
整好想说这些砖哪
Look...
您看啊
Don't worry,
不着急啊
let's wait for the others.
咱们等等后边
No, let's keep moving.
不用等 赶紧走吧
It's fine.
没关系 没关系
It's pretty convenient
这个平时上班也挺近的
living close to work.
挺方便的啊
This way.
这边
Please enter unlock info.
请输入开锁信息
Unlock failed.
开锁失败
Boss,
领导
this is a fingerprint lock.
你这个是指纹锁
My hand's a bit damp.
手有点潮
Unlocked.
已开锁
Go ahead.
进吧
Boss,
领导
where's your bathroom?
你们家卫生间在哪儿啊
Right next door.
就在旁边
-All right. -Go ahead.
好 去吧
I'll go then.
那我先过去啊
Don't rush.
别着急啊
Let me get you slippers.
我给你们拿鞋
I'm in the room.
我在房间
Cover me.
一会帮我打掩护
Boss.
领导
I'm here.
在这儿呢
What's going on?
有情况啊
What's up, Fanggang?
怎么了赵哥
What are you talking about?
什么情况
Are you dating someone?
谈女朋友了
Why do you ask?
怎么这么问啊
I found a hair
我刚才在卫生间
in the bathroom.
发现了一根头发
The length and color
那长度跟颜色
are definitely not yours.
一看就不是你的
It
和
looks like Xiaoning's.
小涂的颜色差不多
What Xiaoning?
什么小涂
What are you talking about?
说什么呢
There must be someone.
一定有人
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理
why are you
我说你怎么
so nosy?
这么八卦啊
Do you think Mr. Ji
你以为人家纪总
is like you,
跟你似的
single dog?
门面惨淡
It's normal for him to have a partner.
人有对象不是很正常吗
How am I single dog?
我怎么门面惨淡了
Before Mr. Ji arrived,
那纪总没来之前
between me,
我
Xu Li, and Li Xiang,
许力 李想
I was considered
那我也
the face of our department.
算得上是个门面担当吧
Yeah,
对呀
and that almost
所以咱们拓展一部
brought down
差点
our department.
垮了
What?
不是
Do you two really think
什么呀
he was the face
你们俩还真承认
of the department?
他门面担当
Look,
领导
boss, sorry for
对不起啊领导
dropping by
我们这波人过来
unannounced.
也没跟你提前打个招呼
Did we interrupt you?
影响你二人世界了吧
Should we
要不
invite your girlfriend
你把弟妹叫来
to join us?
我们一起过
We're...
我们俩
you know,
是吧
in a complicated
目前这个
situation right now.
比较特殊
Complicated?
特殊
Maybe...
要不
Okay,
行
got it.
懂了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
the company
现在公司
is cracking down on personal conduct.
严查个人作风问题
Be careful.
你可得注意啊
Where's Xiaoning?
小涂怎么还没来
Did she get lost?
她不是迷路了
Maybe.
是啊
No, I called her
不是我在超市
several times from the supermarket,
给她打这么多电话
but she still isn't here.
你看她到现在也没来
Your efficiency is questionable.
你看你这办事效率
Let me call her.
我给她打
Then,
那你
go ahead.
那你打
You're really nosy.
赵经理你管得真多
You can't
你是真
stay idle, can you?
闲不了一点啊
If she's not here, I need to find her.
那她没来我不得找到她
Let's play some music, lighten the mood.
放点音乐活跃活跃气氛
How about
要不这样
we have dinner
一会儿咱们吃饭
on the terrace?
去上面的那个露台
There's a spot
上面也有
up there
收拾东西的地方
where we can set up.
咱把东西直接拿上去吧
Sounds good.
好啊
Okay.
行
You have a terrace?
你这儿还有露台呢
Zhao Fanggang,
赵方刚
open the red wine bottle for me.
把那个红酒给我开了
I'll need it
醒一下
when I go up.
我上去就要喝
Am I your servant
我是你佣人
or your butler?
我还是你保姆
It's up and to the left.
上面左拐啊
Fanggang,
小赵哥
I'm almost there,
我马上到
about ten minutes.
预计十分钟左右
Boss,
领导
let me handle it.
我来吧
Okay.
好
Then,
那正好
I'll go change.
我去换身衣服
All right.
好嘞 好嘞 好嘞
You go first.
你先去
Can't you help me with this?
你就不帮我拿一下
You're really ungrateful.
你这人真的是忘恩负义
Where is she?
人呢
Come out,
出来吧
they've all gone upstairs.
他们都已经上去了
My...
我
my legs are numb.
我腿麻了
Let me massage them for you.
我帮你揉揉
No.
不用
The more you touch, the more it hurts.
你越碰我 我越疼
Annoying.
讨厌
Boss,
领导
here you are.
找你半天了你在这儿呢
What's up?
怎么了
Xiaoning texted
小涂发信息说
that she'll be here in ten minutes.
还有十分钟就到了
Let's go downstairs to wait for her.
那咱们就下去等她
We'll welcome
我们 恭迎
her majesty
涂筱柠同学
at doorstep.
大驾光临
All right.
行
Go change first.
那你先换着
Why are you back again?
你怎么又回来了
You guys go ahead.
你们先弄
Mr. Ji and I will wait for Xiaoning.
我跟纪总下去等小涂
Boss,
领导
is there anyone else in your house
你们家除了我们
besides us?
还有别人吗
Of course not.
当然没有了
I just saw
我刚才看见一个人影
a shadow flash by.
唰一下就蹿过去了
Let me check.
我看看
There's no one.
哪有什么人
You're just being paranoid.
整天疑神疑鬼的
Am I?
不至于啊
I'm only in my thirties,
我这才三十多
my eyesight can't be that bad.
眼神就不好使了
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Fanggang,
小赵哥
sorry,
不好意思啊
I'm late.
我来晚了
No worries, come in.
没关系进来吧
Well,
那个
you're doing hot pot today,
今天不是做火锅吗
so I'll help out more.
那我多干点活啊
Fanggang, can I help you?
小赵哥我帮你忙吧
No,
没事 没事
I've got this.
我这边可以了
We can handle it.
我们仨老爷们行
You can see
你看领导那边
if our boss needs any help.
有什么需要帮忙的
Sure.
好
Help me cut this.
帮我把这根切一下
Leave it to me.
来你给我
Need help?
要帮忙吗
Roll up my sleeves for me.
帮我卷一下袖子
Sure.
好
My hands are all messy.
我手上全是料
here.
这边
Boss,
领导
I've prepped
我这边菜
most of the veggies.
备得差不多了
If in short,
要是一会儿不够
I'll cut more.
我再切
Great.
好
Well,
那
it's time
准备 准备
to eat.
咱们开始吧
Okay.
行
Let me take that.
你给我吧
Boss,
领导
here,
来
try this.
吃点这个
I can serve myself.
我自个儿来就行
Let me get you some veggies.
我给你夹点青菜啊
Well,
那个
Mr. Ji,
纪总
let me toast to you.
我敬你一杯啊
Sit down.
坐
All right.
行
Since you
那个自打您
joined the company,
到公司来之后
our section one's business
咱们拓展一部的业务
has been booming.
那是噌噌地往上涨
True.
是
I was
之前
immature before.
是我不懂事
I hope
我希望
you won't
您别 跟我
take it to heart.
介意啊
Cheers.
来
It's all in the past,
都过去了
don't worry about it.
别往心里去啊
Li Xiang,
李想
you're being too formal.
你还是太见外了
Calling him Mr. Ji all the time.
还纪总纪总地叫
Boss,
领导
here,
来
let me toast to you.
我敬您一杯
Drink it yourself.
你自己喝吧
Hey,
我
stop teasing.
讨厌
See,
你看啊
once you get to know each other,
就是两个人熟了之后
you can joke around.
就能开起玩笑了
Let's all toast
这样吧咱们一起
to the boss
敬领导一个
and start calling
以后你们也改口
him boss.
叫领导
Here,
来
boss,
领导
let me toast to you.
那我也敬您一个
Wishing you reach new heights.
祝您早日走上人生巅峰
Okay.
好
Mr. Ji...
那个纪总
I mean,
不
boss, under your leadership,
在领导的带领之下
our section one
咱们拓展一部的业绩
will thrive.
更是飞黄腾达
-Good. -Well said.
是 这个好
Boss, though I'm not drinking,
领导虽然我没有喝酒
my toast is heartfelt.
但都在酒里了
Boss,
领导
may you achieve your goal of a billion.
早日实现一个亿目标
All right.
好
Xiaoning, your turn.
小涂到你了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
happy birthday.
生日快乐
Thank you for your care
谢谢您这段时间的照顾
and understanding.
和包容
Thanks for
那我得
your
谢谢小涂
genuine wishes, Xiaoning.
这个朴实无华的祝福
Let's keep
我们来日方长
working together.
并肩作战
Cheers.
来
Everyone.
大家一起
Bottoms up.
干了啊
Boss,
领导
you can
你不用干了
take it slow.
你慢慢喝
Our section one
咱 拓展一部
is like a big family,
就是相亲相爱的一家人
We make
有钱
money together,
一起赚
we face
有锅
challenges together.
一起扛
And we introduce
有对象
dating partners
也相互
to each other.
介绍 介绍
You just
我看你
want free
就是想骗大家
matchmaking services.
给你做免费的红娘
So what?
那怎么了
I'm not getting any younger.
我年纪也不小了
Wanting to get married is normal.
想结婚也是人之常情
Not everyone is like you,
你以为都跟你似的
playing around.
玩得这么花
Changing partners every day.
一天换一个
Besides,
再说啊
being a family
什么叫
means supporting each other,
相亲相爱的一家人
not just talking about it.
只说不做是嘴把式
Yes.
是
Right?
对吧
Xiaoning,
小涂
you broke up with the guy
我记得给你送花那个
who sent you flowers?
掰了吧
No, I...
不是 我
Let me
我 我这样
introduce you
哥再给你
to someone new.
介绍一个新的
No need.
不用 不用
I'm not
我现在
looking to date now.
不想谈恋爱
Got a new suitor?
有新的追求者了
No,
没有
just focusing
我就想
on my exams.
好好地准备考试
Work is my priority.
工作 工作最要紧
Well, you know...
我跟你说
Saying too much is harassment.
说多了就是骚扰
I think Xiaoning is
我觉得小涂这么做
doing the right thing.
是对的
I heard
我听说
Mr. Ji
纪总
just applied to add new staff
刚向公司申请了
to our section one.
增加部门人员
A new person
下周
is joining next week.
就会来一个新人
Xiaoning,
小涂啊
you must do harder.
你可得加把劲
Don't let the
可千万别
latecomer get ahead.
让后来者居上啊
What were you talking about?
说什么呢
Why so serious?
怎么都这么严肃
Just talking about what we're gonna play.
我们商量一会儿玩点啥
Right!
对了
PS5.
家用电子游戏机
Uno.
桌游
Or Legends of the Three Kingdoms.
还有那个 三国杀
Yes.
对
I don't have any of those.
我们家还真没这些
Does it mean we have
这总不能玩
to play Truth or Dare?
真心话大冒险吧
No way.
是啊
How about checkers?
跳棋怎么样
I have checkers.
我家有跳棋
Good idea!
这玩意好呀
Yeah!
对啊
Okay, I'll get it for you.
行 我给你们拿去
No, I'll get it.
不 不 不
Where is it?
我去 在哪儿呢
It's in the room across from the stairs.
那个楼梯正对着那房间
Okay.
得嘞
It may take your time.
得稍微找找啊
That's okay.
得嘞 得嘞 得嘞
Be quick.
快点啊
I ate too fast.
吃得太急了
Just one small client.
就是流失了一个小客户
It's not your fault.
主要原因也不在你
Sir.
领导
If you say so.
你要这么说的话
This might work.
这可以
I can eat more.
我一会儿再吃一波
What?
啥呀
What's wrong?
咋了这是
I thought you got checkers.
不是让你拿跳棋吗
I didn't open it to check.
我也没打开看
Sorry I got the wrong box.
就 就拿错了
Since we've got it,
既然都拿来了
let's take a look.
就看看吧
This doll is so cute.
这个玩偶好可爱啊
Isn't it?
是吧
Cute little doll.
这不是小娃娃吗
So pretty!
真好看 这个
I didn't realize you can be so romantic.
领导也是用情至深啊
"Your smile is like
你的笑容于我而言
sunshine to me.
如阳光般灿烂
Hope we have more stories
希望我们未来
to tell in the future."
有更多故事可以发生
Good words.
好文笔 好文笔
Here.
来吧
Let's toast to
我们一起
the Heather.
敬白月光
Okay.
来 来 来
Let's toast.
敬 敬 敬
To the Heather.
敬白月光
Here.
来 一起
Were you in relationship when
你上大学的时候
you were in college?
谈过恋爱吗
No.
没有啊
Was there someone you into?
那有喜欢的人吗
Not even one girl
不会连喜欢的人
in your heart?
也没有吧
Of course there was.
当然有
Mr. Ji is so romantic.
领导可真浪漫呀
He still has that doll
这么多年了
after all these years.
还留着那个娃娃呢
Yeah.
是吧
What's that phrase?
有个词叫什么来着
The phrase you said at the toast.
就你们饭桌上说那个词
"The Heather".
白月光啊
The girl must be
那姑娘肯定是
"the one" to Mr. Ji.
领导的白月光
You don't know men.
这你就不懂了吧
When a man can't get it,
男人啊得不到的时候呢
he misses it.
就惦记
When he gets it, he won't cherish it anymore.
得到了就那么回事
Jerk.
渣男
I don't think so.
那可不一定啊
Judging by his character,
以领导这性格
I'm sure he'd be very affectionate
真要和白月光在一起
if he was
那不得
with that girl.
可劲深情
Ling Weiyi wants to see me.
凌惟依找我有事
I'll be home later.
我晚点回去
You're right.
你说得对赵哥
Your judgment is...
你感觉上就
Hello?
喂
Yes.
对
See the location I sent you?
就是我发给你那个位置
Go all the way in,
你一直往里走
and you'll find me.
就能看见我了啊
Ms. Rao.
饶经理
The little boyfriend from last time?
上次那个小男友
Which time?
哪次
The blind date.
相亲会那次
This time is just
这次
a friend.
朋友
Don't wanna be responsible for relationship.
谈了恋爱还不想负责
You're not...
你这是
Not scum but dust.
不是渣 你这是粉末
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
Since you're so sorry for them,
你这么替他们抱不平
I really want to know
我特别想知道啊
if you're envying
你这是羡慕嫉妒恨
them,
他们呢
or you're envying me.
你还是羡慕嫉妒恨我
It's alright, Fanggang.
行了赵哥
Jing won this one.
这轮静姐赢了
Have another round next time.
改日再战
Yeah.
对 对 对
Jing.
姐
Here you are.
来了
Let me introduce.
我给你介绍一下
They're my coworkers.
我们同事
Well,
那个
we're off now.
我们先走了啊
I drank today.
我今天喝酒了
You'll drive.
待会儿下去你开车
Okay.
好
He's just average-looking.
长得也就那样吧
I think he's handsome.
挺帅的呀
Better than the previous one.
比上次那个帅
Hello?
喂
Okay.
好 好
I'm on my way.
马上过来
My ride's here.
我代驾到了
Who'll come with me?
谁跟我走
I'll give you a lift.
我捎你们一段
-We'll grab a cab. -What about Xiaoning?
我们打车 小涂呢
My cab is almost here.
我叫车了也到了
Let's go.
我们走吧
Okay.
好嘞 好嘞
Hello, Ling Weiyi.
喂 凌惟依
Where are you?
你在哪儿
It's not the first time I've learned
我也不是第一次知道
he has someone before.
他有白月光了
I have an ex.
我也有前任
I'm not
我呢
a double-standard.
也不是那种双标的人
I don't mind he having first love
说只允许自己有前任
while I have an ex.
不允许他有白月光
But an ex is different from
但是前任跟白月光
"a Heather".
它可不一样吧
What is it? It's a love
白月光是什么
out of reach yet keeps you craving.
那是爱而不得的执念
We've been together for a couple months.
我们俩在一起几个月了
He still saves the gift
他还留着
for this girl.
要给白月光的礼物
How much and special
你说这个人对他来说
this girl
有多重要
means to him.
有多特别啊
Look at your
你看看你
jealous and
吃醋那样
sulky face.
魂不守舍地
People would think you must
不知道的还以为
love him so dearly.
你爱惨了纪昱恒呢
What the matter with you?
你不对劲
Me?
我怎么了
You were checking your phone all the time.
你刚刚一直玩手机
You weren't listening to me.
根本就没听我说话
Who are you messaging?
给谁发微信呢
Look at your radiant face.
眉飞色舞地
There must be someone,
有情况
and you don't share with me.
还不跟我分享
Spit it out.
说
Who's that man?
到底是谁
You know who he is.
还能有谁啊
Qi Yu?
齐郁啊
You're back together?
你俩和好了
Since when?
什么时候的事啊
Just two days ago.
就前两天
I'm done.
好了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
I told you
我说了
you didn't have to make the trip.
你不用自己跑一趟
I could call a repairman.
我叫人上门一样的
I know.
我知道
I'm a volunteer.
我是自愿的
The repairman isn't
你叫师傅上门
always on time.
不一定准时
Besides, you were alone.
况且你一个人
I could be worried.
我也不放心
No.
不是
I mean,
我是说那个
it's not safe for a girl alone at night.
大晚上一个女孩不安全
How about
要不
I buy you dinner.
我请你吃饭吧
No, thanks.
不用
I mean,
我的意思是说
I don't like to owe people favors.
不喜欢欠别人人情
You know.
你知道的
I know.
我知道
I'm sweating all over.
我出一身臭汗
I'd like to take a shower
趁宿舍熄灯前
before lights out in the dorm.
想好好洗个澡
If you really
你如果实在
want to take a shower,
身上黏得厉害的话
You can do it on the first floor.
你要不就在一楼洗洗吧
I'm on the second floor.
我住二楼
Take a shower here?
在这儿洗啊
Better not.
别了吧
It's not convenient when you are here.
你一个女孩不方便
That's it.
行
I'll go now.
我先撤了啊
And
那个
remember to lock the door
晚上睡觉前
before you go to bed.
把门锁好
I'm taking the trash away.
垃圾给你带走了啊
Okay.
行
Hello?
喂
Is that the security department?
你好请问是保安部吗
Yes.
是的
I'm Ling Weiyi from the front desk.
我是前台的凌惟依
I'd like to ask,
我想问一下
is staff dorm
我们大厦和
near the building
代瑞的集体宿舍
of workplace?
是在一块吗
Yes.
是啊
Could you please send me
具体位置在哪儿
the address of the dorm?
能发给我一下吗
You're the girl from
你是前台那个
the front desk.
小美女
What are you doing here?
你来这里干吗
I'm looking for Qi Yu.
我找齐郁
Does he live here?
他是住这儿吗
He's in the shower.
他在洗澡
Come in and wait.
你进来等他吧
Ma,
小马
have you eaten yet?
你吃饭了吗
Weiyi?
惟依
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
You left your ID at my house.
你身份证落我家了
I'm here to bring it to you.
我给你送过来
You could have called me
你打电话
to pick it up.
让我去取就行了
It's not safe to walk alone
大晚上一个人
at night.
多不安全
Make yourself at home.
你 随便坐啊
Have a drink.
喝水
No, thank you.
不用了
So this is where you live?
你就住这儿啊
You mean dorm?
宿舍吗
It's not bad.
都是这样的
Though it's small,
你别看我们这个宿舍小
it's really cozy.
住起来真蛮舒服的
The closets.
那你说这个柜子
I bought it
是我从
from a roommate who had left the city.
回老家的舍友那儿买的
Do you know how old is it?
你猜多大
Ten years!
十年了
But it's still
还是这么
sturdy and durable.
结实耐用
And
还有
this little table lamp by the bed.
床前这个小台灯
The light of phone screen won't be
晚上看手机的时候
harsh with the lamp on.
一点不晃眼
Here.
对
This
还有这个
bed table.
小桌板
It's really stable on the bed
吃饭的时候铺在床上
when I eat here.
特别稳当
Isn't it simple?
可你这也太简陋了吧
I have another house
我在你们银行附近
near your workplace.
还有一套房子
You can stay there for now.
要不你先借住在我那儿
It'll make it easier for you
这样你上下班
to get to and from work.
每天也方便一点
I really don't need it.
真不需要
Living here and working at the bank
住这儿跟在银行上班
are both temporary.
都是暂时的
"Temporary"?
暂时的
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
Actually, I was planning to take
其实我回星城之前
the civil service exam again
就有打算
before I went back to Xing City.
再次考公务员
The bank's job
银行的工作
is to make ends meet.
就是为了先维持生计
The president knows it.
行长也知道
He said I'm good in many ways.
他觉得我各方面
So he recommended that
素质都不错
I take the police exam.
推荐我去考警察
I've been preparing.
我已经在备考了
But I've heard that
可是我听说
the exams are difficult.
考公务员都很难的
Why do you have to
你为什么非让自己
work so hard?
这么辛苦啊
It's not hard for me.
这有什么辛苦的
That sand bottle
那个沙画瓶
was my first
是我跟他
gift to him
刚在一起的时候
when we first got together.
给他送的第一份礼物
Qi Yu is usually
齐郁这人平时
insensitive.
特别神经大条的
He'd been back home
中间还回老家
for so long.
待了那么久
I thought he'd lost it
我真觉得他早就已经
a long time ago.
把它弄不见了
I didn't realize he had it all the time.
没想到他还一直都带着
Think about it.
你想想看啊
He has a car, a house
其实他在老家
and a stable job
有车有房
in his hometown.
有稳定工作
He could have lived comfortably there.
可以过得很舒服的
But now he's here
但他现在却为了我
for me.
来到了这儿
I went to see his dormitory.
我去看他住的那个环境
I felt sorry for him.
其实心里挺不舒服的
But he's still
但是他整个人的状态
positive.
就是特别积极向上
I can tell
看得出
he's serious about
他对我们这段感情
our relationship.
很认真
He's really given a lot.
他真的付出了挺多的
Yeah.
是
Lu Sijing told me many times
陆思靖也跟我说过
that he
很多回
need to look up to him.
说要向他看齐
But honestly,
但是讲实话啊
they're not
说到底他们俩
the same kind at all.
根本就不是一种人
They're different.
也不一样
In what way?
怎么说
Qi Yu
齐郁呢
will put your needs
会把你的需求
first.
放在第一位
Your needs
你的需求
paramount
在什么时候
at all times.
都是最重要的
Honestly,
讲实话
how many people
现在有几个人
can do that nowadays?
能做到这个份上啊
He deserves to be loved.
他真的值得
I also deserve to be loved!
我也很值得好不好
Of course.
那当然了
Lu Sijing
陆思靖当然
can't match Qi Yu.
比不上我们齐郁啊
They're different
但是其实从骨子里
in the most important part.
他俩就是不一样的
That is, for you,
因为在你这儿
he has already been a history.
陆思靖早就已经翻篇了
But Qi Yu and I
但是齐郁对我来说呢
were just bickering.
顶多算是闹闹别扭
We never got to the point
也从来没有到过
of breaking it off.
要断情绝爱的地步
Yeah.
那倒是
You deserve the best.
你值得最好的
I wish you two
反正祝你们两个
the best of luck
再续前缘
in your relationship,
百年好合
and the best life.
好好的啊
I don't expect the best life.
百年好合可不敢说
I just hope
但是真心希望
our relationship
我们的爱情之路
can be sweet,
能够甜甜蜜蜜地
like old times in college.
像大学那样就行
Unlocked.
已开锁
I'm back.
回来了
You're back so early.
这么快就回来了
I was thinking to pick you up
我还说收拾完之后
after the cleaning.
去接你呢
Why did Ling Weiyi
凌惟依找你
call you out?
什么事啊
She's back together with Qi Yu.
她跟齐郁复合了
They get back together?
复合了
It's great.
那是好事啊
Though I've only met him
虽然我跟齐郁
a few times.
没见过几面
I think he's
但觉得他还是一个
an honest man.
挺实在的人
What?
怎么了
Something's on your mind?
有心事啊
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
Can,
我
can I ask you something?
想问你个问题
Yeah.
可以啊
Sure.
你问
You didn't tell me
你过生日的事情
your birthday.
没有跟我说
Is it because
是因为
there's someone
有更想
you'd rather spend your birthday with?
一起过生日的人吗
Is it really bothering you?
怎么还在想这个问题呀
In fact, very few people
其实我的生日
know my birthday
除了我妈和人力之外
except my mom and HR.
很少有人知道
And I'm not used to
而且我没有
having birthday party.
过生日的习惯
In the old days,
以前的时候呀
my parents
父母
could still be with me
还能陪在我身边
for a happy birthday.
快快乐乐地过一个生日
But after
但是后来
my mom got sick,
我妈生病了以后呀
I rarely had birthdays.
就很少过了
If that's what you
如果你要是
care about,
特别在意的话
we'll spend my birthday
以后我的生日
together from now on,
我们一起过
okay?
好不好
I never thought to
可我也从来没想过
ask him his birthday.
主动去问他的生日
I thought we were good enough.
我以为我们已经很好了
Now I know,
现在看来
there's still a distance.
依旧是隔着距离
What are you thinking?
想什么呢
I'm thinking
我在想
the exams are coming up
月底就要
at the end of the month.
考试了
I should go and study.
我该去复习了
We were
你过生日
in a hurry today.
太匆忙了
I didn't prepare a present for you.
我没有准备礼物
Is there anything you want
你有什么想要的
for your birthday?
生日礼物吗
Can I
我
keep it in mind,
可不可以先记账
and you can give me later
等我想好了
when I have ideas.
再告诉你
Okay.
好
There's been so much
我们之间
between us.
发生了这么多事
Are you still
你心里
harboring the girl out of reach?
还藏着那个白月光吗
You've given me
我念念不忘
the gift I've been longing for
这么多年的礼物
all these years.
你已经送我了
This way.
这边
You're new here.
刚到一个新的环境
You may need to
可能各方面
readjust in many ways.
都需要重新适应一下
Section 1 and 2
一部跟二部
are on the same floor.
都在这层
This is the office
这边是我们
of our Section 1.
拓展一部的办公室
Guys.
各位
Attention, please.
先放一下手上的工作
Hold on.
稍等一下
There's a new
行里有一项
personnel change.
新的人事变动
Let me introduce.
我跟大家同步一下
This is
在我身边的
Tang Yuhui.
唐羽卉
She'll be one of us
即将作为我们的新同事
as a member of Section 1 of BDD.
正式加入拓展一部
Tang.
小唐
Why don't you introduce
你也跟大家
yourself to everyone?
自我介绍一下吧
Okay.
好
Good morning.
大家好
I'm Tang Yuhui.
我叫 唐羽卉
I used to be a lobby manager.
之前是大堂经理
I'm honored
很荣幸
to be in Section 1.
可以来到拓展一部
And I hope that
也希望我的加入
I can give a boost
可以让我们部门
to the section.
如虎添翼
It's almost the end of the year.
也临近年底了
The bank's deposit target
行里给咱们部门
for our department
下达的存款指标
is still not being met.
还有一定的缺口
Let's work together to meet the target
我们大家一起努把力
before the New Year.
争取能够过个好年
I'll leave you to your work.
大家先忙吧
Okay.
好
Yuheng,
师哥
I haven't given you this yet.
这个还没给你呢
Come to my office.
到我办公室来吧
I'm on my way.
我现在就过来
Fanggang.
小赵哥
I got news.
有新情况
What news?
什么情况
The new girl, Tang Yuhui,
刚才新来的唐羽卉
said to have been
说跟纪总
in the same college with Mr. Ji.
是师兄妹关系
I noticed she kept
但是我发现
her eyes on Mr. Ji.
她一直盯着纪总
I know from years of experience that
以我多年的经验来判断
there's something between them.
他俩绝对有事
What thing?
有啥事啊
I've heard that
我之前听说
Tang Yuhui's father is
唐羽卉她爸
the boss of the largest
是本市港口最大的
listed company in the city.
上市公司老总
He's got business with Dairui.
和咱们代瑞有业务往来
That's odd.
那就奇怪了
You see,
你说
this Tang Yuhui is
这唐羽卉
highly educated,
要学历有学历
has a dad in high place,
要关系有关系
and she's pretty.
人还长那么漂亮
She can go to
在代瑞
any of Dairui's departments.
去哪个部门不行啊
Why does she have to
为什么
come to our Section 1
非得来咱拓展一部
instead of Section 2?
不去二部呢
What's your point?
你这话说得
You mean Section 2 is better than us?
二部比咱一部好啊
Absolutely not.
那没有
Tang, with your ability
小唐以你的能力
and resources,
和资源的话
you can go to
完全可以去到一个
a better department.
更好的部门
Why do you want to come here?
为什么想要来拓展一部
I think BDD
我觉得拓展部
has potential.
有发展前景
If HQ is about to
而且如果总部
set up a branch,
要设置分行的话
they'll definitely
肯定会从
pick someone from here.
拓展一二部里选人的
I want to try.
我想试试
You're far-sighted.
眼光还挺长远
Whether you're using
不管你是不是
this place as
把拓展一部
a springboard or not,
当做是一个跳板
as long as you're here,
只要你在这里一天
you need to do your best.
就需要尽力一天
Okay.
嗯
The old friends from college.
师兄 师妹
Is she the girl
那纪总的白月光
who's "out of reach"?
是不是就是她呀
The doll!
那个玩偶
You're right!
对了
Tang Yuhui came here
唐羽卉追纪总
just for Mr. ji...
就是为了
Her hair looks
她的发型
exactly like that doll's.
和那个娃娃一模一样
Dairui
咱们代瑞
doesn't support office romances.
不支持办公室恋情
Mr. Ji must know that.
纪总不是不知道
Rules can also be discarded
在利益资源面前
in the face of resources and profit.
规则有的时候
It's their privilege.
也有绿灯特权
I thought I could be her mentor.
本来还以为是我带她呢
Xu Li.
许力
You got a mirror?
你家有秤吗
No.
没有啊
I can give you one.
我送你一个吧
Great.
太好了
To see who you really are.
自己回家秤秤几斤几两
To her, Mr. Ji is somebody.
他是她的师哥
And you're nobody.
你想得有点多
You rhymed!
单押也算押哦
So you're a rapper?
你也是个说唱歌手
Exactly.
那可不
Yuheng.
师哥
Can Ms. Rao
我能不能
be my mentor?
跟着饶经理啊
I heard about it
在大堂的时候
back in the lobby that
我就听说
she has the best track record.
她的业绩是最好的
She is Tu Xiaoning's mentor.
饶静带了涂筱柠
You can take Mr. Xu.
你就跟着许经理吧
But Xiaoning worked as an intern
可是筱柠姐之前
for 3 years in the lobby.
在大堂三年都没转正
I don't think she has a chance
到这儿应该
to be a permanent employee.
也没什么机会了吧
Mr. Xu seems to be
而且我看许经理
easy-going.
挺好说话的
Why don't she go to Mr. Xu?
要不把她换过去
That may be easier for her.
这样她能轻松一点
She has her own advantages.
涂筱柠有她自己的优势
There's a comprehensive evaluation that
能不能转正
will determine whether she can make it.
看的也是综合考评
If you don't want
如果你不想
to take Mr. Xu,
跟着许经理的话
You can choose Mr. Zhao.
赵经理那儿
He can teach you.
还有一个带新人的名额
I'll choose Mr. Xu.
那我就跟着许经理吧
I trust you can choose
只要是你安排的
the best mentor for me.
那肯定就是最好的
If you have no other questions,
没事的话
go to work.
去忙吧
Okay.
好
Yuheng.
师哥
In fact, I came here
其实我来拓展部
not just because of
不仅仅是因为
its potential.
这儿有发展前景
Is that a girl?
是个女孩啊
You like her?
喜欢的女孩
It's
她
her birthday soon.
快过生日了